<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>This Cute World</title><link href="https://thiscute.world/en/index.xml" rel="self"/><link href="https://thiscute.world/en/"/><updated>2023-08-01T11:40:57+08:00</updated><id>https://thiscute.world/en/</id><author><name>ryan4yin</name></author><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><entry><title type="html">Why do I explore these niche technologies?</title><link href="https://thiscute.world/en/posts/why-i-choose-niche-products/"/><id>https://thiscute.world/en/posts/why-i-choose-niche-products/</id><author><name>ryan4yin</name></author><published>2023-08-01T11:40:57+08:00</published><updated>2023-08-01T11:40:57+08:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<figure>
          <img class="lazyload" src="/en/posts/why-i-choose-niche-products/anime-girls-seagulls.webp" height="2428" width="1134"><figcaption></figcaption>
        </figure><p>I have dabbled with many niche technologies, and this year, the main ones I explored are NixOS, window manager i3/hyprland, and Neovim. NixOS, in particular, took me to a whole new level - I even created an open-source bilingual book <a href="https://github.com/ryan4yin/nixos-and-flakes-book" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">nixos-and-flakes-book</a> to help beginners get started. Additionally, I worked on several NixOS-related open-source projects like <a href="https://github.com/ryan4yin/nix-darwin-kickstarter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">nix-darwin-kickstarter</a> and <a href="https://github.com/ryan4yin/nix-config" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ryan4yin/nix-config</a>, which all received positive feedback.</p>
<p>Based on my experiences with these niche technologies and the frequent questions I receive (e.g., why did I choose <a href="nixos.org/" rel="">NixOS</a> / <a href="https://github.com/Neovim/Neovim" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Neovim</a> / <a href="https://flypy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Flypy Chinese Input Method</a>? What are their advantages? Can they really improve productivity?), I would like to briefly share my thoughts on them.</p>
<h2 id="what-are-niche-technologies" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#what-are-niche-technologies" class="header-mark"></a>What are niche technologies?</h2><p>&ldquo;Niche&rdquo; refers to being different from the mainstream. Niche technologies are those with a relatively smaller user base within their respective domains.</p>
<p>According to this definition, I can list some niche technologies I have encountered in different fields:</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Domain</th>
<th>Niche Technologies</th>
<th>Mainstream Technologies</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Text Editors</td>
<td>Neovim, Emacs</td>
<td>VSCode, Pycharm, IDEA</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Chinese Input Methods</td>
<td>Double Pinyin, Flypy, Wubi, Erbi, Zhengma, Lingxingsuying</td>
<td>Intelligent Pinyin</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Linux OS</td>
<td>NixOS, Gentoo, Arch Linux</td>
<td>Ubuntu, Fedora</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Window Managers</td>
<td>i3, hyprland</td>
<td>KDE, GNOME</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Most people tend to choose mainstream technologies in these fields due to their lower learning curve and ease of use. I was once part of the majority, but I gradually discovered the advantages of niche technologies, which led me to try and eventually transition to them.</p>
<h2 id="what-are-the-characteristics-of-these-niche-technologies" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#what-are-the-characteristics-of-these-niche-technologies" class="header-mark"></a>What are the characteristics of these niche technologies?</h2><p>Niche technologies obviously have some advantages to attract a portion of users and make them choose these technologies over mainstream ones.</p>
<p>Based on my personal experience with these niche technologies, they share some notable common characteristics.</p>
<p>Firstly, they have a common downside: <strong>higher learning curve and more time required to get familiar with them during the initial stages</strong>.</p>
<p>This filters out the majority of users, and only those who enjoy tinkering and embracing challenges will be willing to explore these niche technologies.</p>
<p>For instance, with the Wubi input method, the learning curve is steep, requiring a significant amount of time to memorize the key arrangement and practice, leading to a challenging input experience in the early stages. To achieve the typing speed you had with an intelligent Pinyin method, you might need to practice Wubi for at least an hour a day consistently for a month (and perhaps even more).</p>
<p>Other shape-based input methods have similar characteristics. I opted for Flypy as a compromise; it has a lower learning curve compared to Wubi, and after mastering it, I can enjoy a similar input experience to Wubi.</p>
<p>Now, let&rsquo;s discuss their common advantages:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>High customizability</strong>: Users can freely customize various functions according to their needs.</li>
<li><strong>Strong sense of control and excellent user experience</strong>: The high level of customization gives users a sense of complete control while using these technologies, resulting in an excellent user experience.</li>
<li><strong>High user retention and active communities</strong>: Users continuously explore, learn, and customize these technologies, creating a strong sense of belonging within the communities.</li>
</ol>
<p>Due to these reasons, once users successfully familiarize themselves with a niche technology (e.g., shape-based input methods, Neovim/Emacs editors), it becomes challenging for them to revert to the previous mainstream solutions. They will find the previous solutions less convenient and enjoyable.</p>
<h2 id="why-do-i-explore-these-niche-technologies" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#why-do-i-explore-these-niche-technologies" class="header-mark"></a>Why do I explore these niche technologies?</h2><p>I have explored various niche technologies, and curiosity is the primary reason. However, what makes me stick with them is their excellent user experience.</p>
<p>For instance, with Neovim editor and Hyprland window manager, once configured, they are aesthetically pleasing! Moreover, Neovim is exceptionally fast, even too fast! This speed may not impress those who haven&rsquo;t experienced VSCode / IDEA before, but once you get used to it, you&rsquo;ll find the speed truly impressive, just like the character Tu Hongyu exclaims in the Three-Body Problem (550W is too fast! This speed is too fast!).</p>
<p>Additionally, after mastering these technologies, I find them enjoyable to use. The keyboard-driven interaction provides a sense of control and smoothness similar to shape-based input methods (elegant, so elegant!).</p>
<p><figure><img src="./hyprland_2023-07-29_1.webp" width="85%"/><figcaption>
            <h4>My NixOS &#43; Hyprland Desktop</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure><img src="./hyprland_2023-07-29_2.webp" width="85%"/><figcaption>
            <h4>My Neovim Editor</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>
</p>
<p>Similarly, my love for NixOS is based on similar reasons. NixOS with its declarative, reproducible (consistent runtime environment), OS as Code features aligns perfectly with what an operations enthusiast like me desires. I couldn&rsquo;t wait to use it and even wanted to improve it promptly to make it suitable for more scenarios.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A few days ago, I saw a comment from a foreign netizen on 4chan (although the language was a bit extreme, I still somewhat agreed&hellip;):
Completely and utterly unacceptable. Imagine having a tool that can&rsquo;t even properly undo an operation and then relying on it to manage an operating system. <code>apt</code>, <code>pip</code>, <code>pm</code>, <code>rpm</code>, <code>pacman</code>, whatever are all a mad fucking joke.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="can-niche-tools-or-technologies-improve-productivity" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#can-niche-tools-or-technologies-improve-productivity" class="header-mark"></a>Can niche tools or technologies improve productivity?</h2><p>Many people claim that niche tools like Neovim editor, i3 window manager, and shape-based input methods can boost productivity, but I believe it is a misconception. In fact, many of these tools or technologies can be time-consuming distractions, driven by one&rsquo;s interests to continuously explore their boundaries and adjust configurations to better suit individual needs. During the initial phase, the time invested in these endeavors often outweighs the saved time from increased productivity.</p>
<p>So, ultimately, trying to use these technologies to significantly boost productivity is not realistic. They can improve your efficiency, but to a limited extent, unless your typing speed is the limiting factor in your productivity, emmm&hellip;</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Of course, there are some special scenarios where shape-based input methods like Wubi can indeed significantly improve input efficiency, especially when dealing with rare characters.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Or some may argue that once you become completely proficient, vim/emacs makes it easier to enter a state of flow? That is also difficult to say.</p>
<h2 id="so-what-are-the-benefits-of-tinkering-with-these-things" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#so-what-are-the-benefits-of-tinkering-with-these-things" class="header-mark"></a>So, what are the benefits of tinkering with these things?</h2><p>If we look at it from a purely pragmatic perspective, there may not be many benefits; it&rsquo;s like playing games, just spending leisure time.</p>
<figure><img src="./useless-work.jpg" width="35%"/><figcaption>
            <h4>Why do you always delve into these things that are useless for the business? (teasing tone)</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>However, compared to doing something boring for leisure, there are some useful takeaways. For instance, when I encounter a bug in AstroNvim</p>
<p>, I provide a PR to the upstream repository. When I find that NixOS documentation is inadequate, I write my own documentation and share it. If I notice that NixOS lacks support for a specific development board I have, I might try to port it. And if I find that a certain tool lacks a feature I want, I might just write one myself.</p>
<p>The experiences gained, open-source projects created, PRs left in upstream repositories, and the appreciation received in the community all feel valuable. It may not necessarily have business value, but it&rsquo;s fun, and you get to make friends, help others, and leave your mark in the open-source community - isn&rsquo;t that interesting?</p>
<p>Linus, when he first created Linux, did it <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/160171.Just_for_Fun" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">just for fun</a>.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title type="html">NixOS &amp;amp; Nix Flakes - A Guide for Beginners</title><link href="https://thiscute.world/en/posts/nixos-and-flake-basics/"/><id>https://thiscute.world/en/posts/nixos-and-flake-basics/</id><author><name>ryan4yin</name></author><published>2023-05-10T21:23:28+08:00</published><updated>2023-06-22T02:50:00+08:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<figure>
          <img class="lazyload" src="/en/posts/nixos-and-flake-basics/nixos-and-flakes-book.webp" height="2219" width="800"><figcaption></figcaption>
        </figure><p>Since the article is so long now, for the convenience of readers, the content of this post has been moved to a separate site:</p>
<ul>
<li>Document Site: <a href="https://nixos-and-flakes.thiscute.world/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://nixos-and-flakes.thiscute.world/</a></li>
<li>GitHub Repo: <a href="https://github.com/ryan4yin/nixos-and-flakes-book" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/ryan4yin/nixos-and-flakes-book</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Thanks for the feedback, criticism, suggestions from <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NixOS/comments/14fvz1q/comment/jp4xhj3/?context=3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Reddit</a>â¤ï¸</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title type="html">Summary of My 2021</title><link href="https://thiscute.world/en/posts/2021-summary/"/><id>https://thiscute.world/en/posts/2021-summary/</id><author><name>ryan4yin</name></author><published>2022-01-23T01:40:00+08:00</published><updated>2022-01-23T01:40:00+08:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<figure>
          <img class="lazyload" src="/en/posts/2021-summary/wrapped_ryan4yin.webp" height="2650" width="1560"><figcaption></figcaption>
        </figure><h2 id="gossip" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#gossip" class="header-mark"></a>Gossip</h2><p>Another year has passed in the twinkling of an eye, and this New year, the global epidemic has set a new record. After Christmas, the daily increase in the United States has directly exceeded 1 million. In China, poor management in Xi&rsquo;an has led to hunger.</p>
<p>COVID-19 has been for more than two years.</p>
<p>Back to the point, after leaving from W Company at the beginning of this year, I was very lucky to join the current company, Mobiuspace, and I was mixed in the process of integrating into Mobiuspace.
However, I am quite satisfied with the overall results, the current work has been on the right track, but also found a lot of opportunities.</p>
<h2 id="life" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#life" class="header-mark"></a>Life</h2><ul>
<li>In January, I set up this Blog, and I met <a href="https://chee5e.space/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@Cheese</a>ï¼Œ@Cheese helped me adjust the style of the &ldquo;Friends&rdquo; page, thanks him very much~</li>
<li>In February, I fired my boss, and then what to say? I suddenly felt open-minded and changed my mindset 180 degrees. It was great, but I was actually very worried about my shortcomings in all aspects. Anyway, I&rsquo;m in a complicated mood. I talked a lot with <a href="https://sanshiliuxiao.top/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@æ˜¯æ ¼å­å•Š</a>, <a href="https://chee5e.space/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@Cheese</a> and former colleagues). Thank you very much for helping me sort out my thoughts and giving me an affirmation. At the same time, I was recommended by <a href="https://chee5e.space/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@Cheese</a> and started using twitter.</li>
<li>I climbed the mountain every day to see the scenery, bought a hammock to take a nap in the park, practiced the harmonica and bamboo flute, and played like this for a month.
<ul>
<li><figure><img src="/images/2021-summary/hammock.webp"/>
</figure>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>In March, I started looking for a job. After meeting with several companies, I was very lucky to enter Mobiuspace and became a new SRE. The experience of a year in Mobiuspace is written in the &ldquo;work&rdquo; section, which is skipped here.</li>
<li>At the end of March, I watched the movie &ldquo;Raya and The Last Dragon&rdquo; (the only movie I watched in 2021), and the ending song was very good.</li>
<li>In April, by various coincidences, I unexpectedly found that my junior high school classmate&rsquo;s residence was less than one kilometer away from me. I had a meal of hometown food and bayberry wine at his house. It tasted very good!</li>
<li>In August, my two cousin came to Shenzhen for a summer internship. I crossed Shenzhen&rsquo;s east-west coastline with them. The scenery was great, but we were really hot and thirsty on the way.</li>
<li>In October
<ul>
<li>Joined Mobiuspace&rsquo;s surfing team, surfing and have a seaside barbecue for the first time.</li>
<li>Bought roller skates, learned reverse skating and step steering, and reviewed some basic skills learned in college.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>In December, Bought a YunMi RO Filterred Water Dispenser, and many kinds of tea. Currently I prefer to drink <strong>Black Tea</strong>, such as Dianhong - Yunnan Gold, Redsunion Keemun.
<ul>
<li><figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/images/2021-summary/yunmi-ro-filterred-water-dispenser.webp" title="/images/2021-summary/yunmi-ro-filterred-water-dispenser.webp" data-thumbnail="/images/2021-summary/yunmi-ro-filterred-water-dispenser.webp" data-sub-html="<h2>YunMi RO Filterred Water Dispenser</h2>">
        <img
            
            loading="lazy"
            src="/images/2021-summary/yunmi-ro-filterred-water-dispenser.webp"
            srcset="/images/2021-summary/yunmi-ro-filterred-water-dispenser.webp, /images/2021-summary/yunmi-ro-filterred-water-dispenser.webp 1.5x, /images/2021-summary/yunmi-ro-filterred-water-dispenser.webp 2x"
            sizes="auto"
            alt="/images/2021-summary/yunmi-ro-filterred-water-dispenser.webp">
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">YunMi RO Filterred Water Dispenser</figcaption>
    </figure></li>
<li><figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/images/2021-summary/my-tea.webp" title="/images/2021-summary/my-tea.webp" data-thumbnail="/images/2021-summary/my-tea.webp" data-sub-html="<h2>All kinds of tea</h2>">
        <img
            
            loading="lazy"
            src="/images/2021-summary/my-tea.webp"
            srcset="/images/2021-summary/my-tea.webp, /images/2021-summary/my-tea.webp 1.5x, /images/2021-summary/my-tea.webp 2x"
            sizes="auto"
            alt="/images/2021-summary/my-tea.webp">
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">All kinds of tea</figcaption>
    </figure></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>In January 2022, I bought Anime PVC Figures for the first time. After putting these figures, I felt that my room was more youthful and colorful.
<ul>
<li><figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/images/2021-summary/Posts-and-Garage-Kit.webp" title="/images/2021-summary/Posts-and-Garage-Kit.webp" data-thumbnail="/images/2021-summary/Posts-and-Garage-Kit.webp" data-sub-html="<h2>Anime PVC Figures and Anime Figure Painting in my room</h2>">
        <img
            
            loading="lazy"
            src="/images/2021-summary/Posts-and-Garage-Kit.webp"
            srcset="/images/2021-summary/Posts-and-Garage-Kit.webp, /images/2021-summary/Posts-and-Garage-Kit.webp 1.5x, /images/2021-summary/Posts-and-Garage-Kit.webp 2x"
            sizes="auto"
            alt="/images/2021-summary/Posts-and-Garage-Kit.webp">
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">Anime PVC Figures and Anime Figure Painting in my room</figcaption>
    </figure></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="readings" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#readings" class="header-mark"></a>Readings</h2><ul>
<li>After resigning at the beginning of the year, I went sightseeing, and my mind was a little more calm. I read more than half of the book &ldquo;From Lost to Found the Pacific Crest Trail&rdquo;.</li>
<li>In June, the community organized us to get vaccinated against COVID-19, I read the book &ldquo;Youth Post Station - A Portrait of Working Girls in Shenzhen&rdquo; in the waiting room, which is mainly about the lives of working girls in the 1980s and 1990s. The writing is very real and the feelings are very delicate.</li>
<li>At the end of the year, my second grandfather died. After attending the funeral, I vaguely found some profound changes in my mind. I finished reading &ldquo;Moon Palace&rdquo;, which tells the tragic life of the protagonist.</li>
<li>Most of the rest of my spare time, boring, do not want to learn anything, do not want to exercise, so I read a lot of web novels to pass the time.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="music" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#music" class="header-mark"></a>Music</h2><p>After resigning at the beginning of the year, I practiced the bamboo flute and the blues harmonica for some time, but then it was basically silent after I got a job.</p>
<p>On the whole, I have made little progress this year.</p>
<figure><img src="/images/2021-summary/midi-keyboard-flute-harmonica.webp"/>
</figure>

<h2 id="working---the-year-i-work-in-mobiuspace" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#working---the-year-i-work-in-mobiuspace" class="header-mark"></a>Working - The year I work in Mobiuspace</h2><p>When I first joined Mobiuspace in March, I was curious, but I was so cautious that I couldn&rsquo;t believe I could get into such a great company. I felt like I was out of luck.
After all, Mobiuspace, whether it is the level of colleagues or the working atmosphere, or the number of customers, compared with my last company is qualitatively different.</p>
<p><figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/images/2021-summary/workstation-1.webp" title="/images/2021-summary/workstation-1.webp" data-thumbnail="/images/2021-summary/workstation-1.webp" data-sub-html="<h2>My first station in Mobiuspace</h2>">
        <img
            
            loading="lazy"
            src="/images/2021-summary/workstation-1.webp"
            srcset="/images/2021-summary/workstation-1.webp, /images/2021-summary/workstation-1.webp 1.5x, /images/2021-summary/workstation-1.webp 2x"
            sizes="auto"
            alt="/images/2021-summary/workstation-1.webp">
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">My first station in Mobiuspace</figcaption>
    </figure>
After getting familiar with the contents and methods of the work, leader tried his best to give me the work that best matched my interests, helping me solve problems, and at the same time giving me great autonomy, which was really great.</p>
<p>However, a high degree of autonomy also brings higher difficulty in work. I have been in a hurry, confused, and even self-doubted when I encounter difficulties. I am worried about whether I will run away the next day.</p>
<p>But fortunately, I still have the ability to adjust my mindset, take responsibility and finish the work step by step.</p>
<p>When there were several delays in my work, leader accompanied me to work overtime. After the work was done, he took me to a big dinner to reward myself. I really thanked him for his help and support.</p>
<p><figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/images/2021-summary/workstation-2.webp" title="/images/2021-summary/workstation-2.webp" data-thumbnail="/images/2021-summary/workstation-2.webp" data-sub-html="<h2>My new station, near the floor-to-ceiling window, the view is great.</h2>">
        <img
            
            loading="lazy"
            src="/images/2021-summary/workstation-2.webp"
            srcset="/images/2021-summary/workstation-2.webp, /images/2021-summary/workstation-2.webp 1.5x, /images/2021-summary/workstation-2.webp 2x"
            sizes="auto"
            alt="/images/2021-summary/workstation-2.webp">
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">My new station, near the floor-to-ceiling window, the view is great.</figcaption>
    </figure></p>
<p>Looking back at the summary and outlook for 2020, I find that the actual progress this year is very different from what I expected last year. The initial goal was only about 10% achieved, but because I was exposed to a lot of unexpected things, I was generally satisfied:</p>
<ul>
<li>It is a great gain to be familiar with the culture and working style of the new company - Mobiuspace, and my working style has been greatly improved.</li>
<li>Contact and be familiar with Mobiuspace&rsquo;s AWS online environment
<ul>
<li>Responsible for maintaining the online Kubernetes management platform, the first time I came into contact with the online cluster peak QPS was tens of thousands. It is of great significance that I have changed from being careful at the beginning to becoming a veteran now.</li>
<li>Using python to write several Kubernetes management platform services, this is also my first time to write online services, quite a sense of achievement</li>
<li>In the second half of the year, I spent a lot of energy on the analysis and control of AWS cost, and got some good results, which benefited a lot.</li>
<li>Learned the simple use of Nginx, just enough to maintain the company&rsquo;s pre-existing Nginx proxy configuration.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Lead the completion of &ldquo;create a new K8s cluster and migrate the services to the new cluster&rdquo;. Although it is not a very difficult thing, but this should be my greatest achievement in 2021.
<ul>
<li>I also encountered all kinds of problems in the process of upgrading. When I first upgraded and migrated, I prepared for a long time and panicked. As a result, there was still something wrong with some of the services during the upgrade. I was really confused at that time.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Casually wrote a few demo of Go, and made little progress.</li>
<li>Learning the rust language for a week, quickly finished reading The Book, and rewrote a <code>video2chars</code> in rust</li>
<li>Learned the underlying principle of Linux container: cgroups/namespace technology, and implemented a demo with go/rust</li>
<li>Learned various network interfaces and <code>iptables</code> of Linux</li>
<li>Be familiar with PromQL/Grafana</li>
</ul>
<p>If I give myself a score, it&rsquo;s &ldquo;good&rdquo;. Because I am not very enterprising, so the result can not be called &ldquo;excellent&rdquo;.</p>
<p>By the way, the new office of Mobiuspace is really great. See my twitter for detailsï¼š</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="zh" dir="ltr">æ–°åŠå…¬åŒºçœŸå¥½å‘ï½<br><br>å€¼æ­¤è‰¯è¾°ç¾æ™¯ï¼Œå¥½æƒ³æ•´ä¸ªæ¦»æ¦»ç±³åå«ï¼Œååœ¨è§’è½çš„è½åœ°çª—è¾¹å·¥ä½œğŸ¤£<br>é‚£ç§ä½¿ç”¨å…¬å…±è®¾æ–½å·¥ï¼ˆmoï¼‰ä½œï¼ˆyuï¼‰çš„ä¹è¶£ï¼Œä»¥åŠå¹³å¸¸å·¥ä½è§ä¸åˆ°çš„æ™¯è‰²äº¤ç›¸è¾‰æ˜ ï¼Œæ˜¯ä¸å¤ªå¥½è¡¨è¿°çš„å¥‡å¦™ä½“éªŒ <a href="https://t.co/FASffzw8N3">pic.twitter.com/FASffzw8N3</a></p>&mdash; ryan4yin | æ–¼æ¸…æ¨‚ (@ryan4yin) <a href="https://twitter.com/ryan4yin/status/1482891448731070466?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 17, 2022</a></blockquote> <script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script> 
<h2 id="a-sense-of-technology" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#a-sense-of-technology" class="header-mark"></a>A Sense of Technology</h2><ul>
<li>Istio Service Mesh: Realize that it is a bit heavy, and its development does not necessarily match our needs
<ul>
<li>The cost of the Sidecar model is relatively high, and without tuning, it will bring a 1/3 to 1/4 increase in the cost of the service, as well as a increase of delay.</li>
<li>Thinking about whether to continue to invest in Istio or to switch to other options.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Service Mesh is still evolving rapidly, and the future trend should be eBPF + Envoy + WASM.
<ul>
<li>Cilium&rsquo;s eBPF-based Service Mesh is a new trend (it falls back to Per-Node Proxy mode when using advanced features). It&rsquo;s expected to hit other Service Mesh of Sidecar mode in terms of cost and delay.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>As for the log of K8s cluster, we currently use a self-developed system based on gelf protocol, but there are a lot of problems.
<ul>
<li>From the point of view of improving the maintainability and ease of use of the log system, loki is worth exploring.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>In terms of K8s cluster management, I think the upgrade iteration of the cluster can be done more automatically and reliably. Next year, we can explore more in the direction of multi-cluster management.</li>
<li><a href="https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/configure-pod-container/quality-service-pod/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pod Service Quality</a>:
For non-core services, the amount of requests resources can be appropriately reduced instead of fully reserved (<code>Guaranteed</code>) to improve resource utilization.</li>
<li>The official HPA capability is not enough. Our developers needs to scale the services based on QPS/Queue or other parameters. We should continue to promote the landing of <a href="https://github.com/kedacore/keda" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">KEDA</a>.</li>
<li>In terms of cost control, I realized the benefits of ARM architecture and AWS Spot EC2.</li>
<li>There is a lot of potential room for optimization of cross-area traffic cost.</li>
<li>AI has landed in various fields, affecting our daily use of voice navigation, song synthesis, speech synthesis and many other fields, including, of course, scenarios related to SRE work: AIOps</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="prospects-of-2022" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#prospects-of-2022" class="header-mark"></a>Prospects of 2022</h2><h3 id="on-the-side-of-technology" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#on-the-side-of-technology" class="header-mark"></a>On the Side of Technology</h3><p>The outlook for this year is more focused. I strive to achieve 50%, which will be a big breakthrough.</p>
<ol>
<li>Proficient in Go and use in at least two projects
<ol>
<li>To forge iron, one must be strong. Coding is the foundation of IT.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Learn kubebuilder, k8s source code.</li>
<li>Network Technologies
<ol>
<li>Service Mesh - Istio</li>
<li>Network Proxy - Envoy/APISIX</li>
<li>K8s Network Plugins: Cilium + eBPF</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Optimization of cost and Service Stability of AWS EKS.
<ol>
<li>Save the cost of <code>DataTransfer-Regional-Bytes</code>.</li>
<li>K8s new featureï¼š<a href="https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/services-networking/topology-aware-hints/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Topology Aware Hints</a></li>
<li>Istio: <a href="https://istio.io/latest/docs/tasks/traffic-management/locality-load-balancing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Locality Load Balancing</a></li>
<li>Optimize the EC2 Instance Typeï¼š
<ol>
<li>Use the more appropriate instance types</li>
<li>Use Instance of ARM architecture, to reduce cost and increase efficiency</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Popularize gRPC protocol</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Get through the local development environment and the running environment on the cloud
<ol>
<li><a href="https://github.com/nocalhost/nocalhost" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">nocalhost</a></li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Multicluster Application Deployment and Disaster Recovery
<ol>
<li>karmada</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Explore new technologies and other possibilitiesï¼ˆLow priorityï¼‰
<ol>
<li>Kubernetes-based Service platform, Future Development Direction
<ol>
<li>kubevela</li>
<li>buildpack</li>
<li>should I promote GitOps</li>
<li>openkruise</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Development of Serverless platform
<ol>
<li>Knative</li>
<li>OpenFunction</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Machine learning / Deep learning: I would like to try to apply AI to music, voice, SRE and other areas I am interested in&hellip;</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>
<p>It can be expected that there will be so many opportunities for the SRE team in 2022. I really look forward to which parts I can be responsible for and what results I can achieve.</p>
<h3 id="on-the-side-of-life" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#on-the-side-of-life" class="header-mark"></a>On the Side of Life</h3><ul>
<li>Sports:
<ul>
<li>Practice roller skating well and learn some tricks, at least twice a month.</li>
<li>Make more than three short trips</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Music
<ul>
<li>Learn music theory again&hellip;</li>
<li>Practice MIDI Keyboard.</li>
<li>Learn Synthesizer V  Stduio Pro + Qingsu AI. Cover some of my favorite songs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Reading: The list is as follows. Read at least one of them in a month.
<ul>
<li>Literature
<ul>
<li><input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> No Longer Human,  Osamu Dazai</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> The End of Your Life Book club,  Will Schwalbe</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> One Hundred Years of Solitude, Gabriel Garcia Marquez</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Love in the Time of Cholera, Gabriel Garcia Marquez</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Sophie&rsquo;s World</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Stories of Your Life and Others, Ted Chiang</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> ã€Šæ²ˆä»æ–‡çš„ååŠç”Ÿã€‹</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> ã€Šæˆ‘ä¸åœ°å›ã€‹</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> ã€Šå°†é¥®èŒ¶ã€‹</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> ã€ŠMy Country and My People - æ—è¯­å ‚ã€‹</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> ã€Šæˆ¿æ€çªçš„åˆæ‹ä¹å›­ã€‹</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>social &amp; sciences
<ul>
<li><input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Death Is But a Dream: I want to know more about &ldquo;death&rdquo; this year.</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> ã€Šæ€æ ·å¾æœç¾ä¸½å°‘å¥³ã€‹ï¼šå“ˆå“ˆ</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Harper Perennial Modern Classics</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Social Psychology</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> The Courage to Be Disliked</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> The Body: A Guide for Occupants</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> The Structure of Scientific Revolutions</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Deng Xiaoping and the Transformation of China</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> On China</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> ã€Šåˆ˜æ“è¥¿æ–¹ç°ä»£æ€æƒ³è®²ä¹‰ã€‹</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> The Order of Time</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> The Universe in Your Hand</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> ã€Šåœ†åœˆæ­£ä¹‰-ä½œä¸ºè‡ªç”±å‰æçš„ä¿¡å¿µã€‹</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> What Do You Say After You Say Hello?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Technology
<ul>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Complexity: A Guided Tour</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Site Reliability Engineering: How Google Runs Production Systems</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> The Phoenix Project - A Novel About IT, DevOps, and Helping Your Business Win</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> The Mythical Man Month and Other Essays on Software Engineering</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> ã€Šç»©æ•ˆä½¿èƒ½ï¼šè¶…è¶Š OKRã€‹</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Powerful: Building a Culture of Freedom and Responsibility</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> ã€Šå¹•åäº§å“-æ‰“é€ çªç ´å¼æ€ç»´ã€‹</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Professional Linux Kernel Architecture</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> <a href="https://man7.org/tlpi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Linux Programming Interface: A Linux and UNIX System Programming Handbook</a></li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Refactoring - Improving the Design of Existing Code</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> How Networks Work</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="in-summary" class="headerLink">
    <a href="#in-summary" class="header-mark"></a>In Summary</h2><p>At the beginning of 2021, my friend and I gave myself the expectation ofã€Œæ‹†ç ´ç‰ç¬¼é£å½©å‡¤ï¼Œé¡¿å¼€é‡‘é”èµ°è›Ÿé¾™ã€, which felt that it had really come true.</p>
<p>This year, I hope to be able to &ldquo;Going up one more storey&rdquo; both in life and at work.</p>
]]></content></entry><entry><title type="html">The End of Another Semester</title><link href="https://thiscute.world/en/posts/the-end-of-another-semester/"/><id>https://thiscute.world/en/posts/the-end-of-another-semester/</id><author><name>ryan4yin</name></author><published>2017-06-27T01:28:45+08:00</published><updated>2017-06-27T01:28:45+08:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<figure>
          <img class="lazyload" src="/en/posts/the-end-of-another-semester/5-centimeters-per-second.webp" height="1920" width="1080"><figcaption></figcaption>
        </figure><!-- Love Story - The Piano Guys -->
<meting-js server="netease" type="song" id="29460780" theme="#448aff"></meting-js>
<p>Ah, there are still ten days to get rid of the city and return to that reassuring mountain forest, waiting and anxious, wondering why the remaining ten days are so difficult.</p>
<p>The final review is a mess again. I am really lazy&hellip;</p>
<p>It is so unrealistic for me to have such a big dream that I have finished thousands of lines of code. I kind of want to accept my fate.</p>
<p>After one o&rsquo;clock in the middle of the night, I was still not used to the air conditioner in the bedroom, but the cool breeze on the aisle balcony is very comfortable, and the serenity of the city now also has a bit of charm.</p>
<p>But anyway, I really want to go home.</p>
]]></content></entry></feed>