<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Tech - Category - This Cute World</title><link>https://thiscute.world/en/categories/tech/</link><description>Tech - Category - This Cute World</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 10:10:22 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thiscute.world/en/categories/tech/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>KubeCon China 2024 Adventure</title><link>https://thiscute.world/en/posts/kubecon-china-2024/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 10:10:22 +0800</pubDate><author><name>ryan4yin</name></author><guid>https://thiscute.world/en/posts/kubecon-china-2024/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/kubecon-china-2024/kubecon-china-2024-linus.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>PrefaceI had known for a while that KubeCon China would be held in Hong Kong this year, and while I was interested, I initially got deterred by the steep price of KubeCon tickets.
Sometimes you just have to believe in the magic of luck. By a twist of fate, I learned about KubeCon&rsquo;s &lsquo;End User Ticket Program&rsquo; from my friend @Kev and snagged a ticket for free. I also invited three friends from the 0xFFFF Community,@Chever-John,@0xdeadbeef, and@MingLLuo, to join in.]]></description></item><item><title>OS as Code - My Experience of NixOS</title><link>https://thiscute.world/en/posts/my-experience-of-nixos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 16:26:21 +0800</pubDate><author><name>ryan4yin</name></author><guid>https://thiscute.world/en/posts/my-experience-of-nixos/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/my-experience-of-nixos/nixos-and-flakes-book-202402.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>It&rsquo;s February 2024, exactly 10 months since I started using NixOS. The beginner notes I wrote initially have received a lot of positive feedback and some sponsorships, becoming one of the most popular entry-level tutorials in the entire community. Since I created a dedicated GitHub repository and a separate documentation site for it in June 2023, it has garnered 1189 stars, and besides me, 37 other readers have submitted PRs:]]></description></item><item><title>Why do I explore these niche technologies?</title><link>https://thiscute.world/en/posts/why-i-choose-niche-products/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 11:40:57 +0800</pubDate><author><name>ryan4yin</name></author><guid>https://thiscute.world/en/posts/why-i-choose-niche-products/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/posts/why-i-choose-niche-products/anime-girls-seagulls.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>I have dabbled with many niche technologies, and this year, the main ones I explored are NixOS, window manager i3/hyprland, and Neovim. NixOS, in particular, took me to a whole new level - I even created an open-source bilingual booknixos-and-flakes-book to help beginners get started. Additionally, I worked on several NixOS-related open-source projects like nix-darwin-kickstarter and ryan4yin/nix-config, which all received positive feedback.
Based on my experiences with these niche technologies and the frequent questions I receive (e.</description></item><item><title>NixOS &amp; Nix Flakes - A Guide for Beginners</title><link>https://thiscute.world/en/posts/nixos-and-flake-basics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 21:23:28 +0800</pubDate><author><name>ryan4yin</name></author><guid>https://thiscute.world/en/posts/nixos-and-flake-basics/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/posts/nixos-and-flake-basics/nixos-and-flakes-book.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>Since the article is so long now, for the convenience of readers, the content of this post has been moved to a separate site:
Document Site: https://nixos-and-flakes.thiscute.world/ GitHub Repo: https://github.com/ryan4yin/nixos-and-flakes-book Thanks for the feedback, criticism, suggestions fromReddit❤️</description></item><item><title>Summary of My 2021</title><link>https://thiscute.world/en/posts/2021-summary/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 01:40:00 +0800</pubDate><author><name>ryan4yin</name></author><guid>https://thiscute.world/en/posts/2021-summary/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/2021-summary/wrapped_ryan4yin.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>GossipAnother year has passed in the twinkling of an eye, and this New year, the global epidemic has set a new record. After Christmas, the daily increase in the United States has directly exceeded 1 million. In China, poor management in Xi&rsquo;an has led to hunger.
COVID-19 has been for more than two years.
Back to the point, after leaving from W Company at the beginning of this year, I was very lucky to join the current company, Mobiuspace, and I was mixed in the process of integrating into Mobiuspace.]]></description></item></channel></rss>